♪ ♪
Hi, this is Linda Hansfield.
I can't take your
call right now,
but if you leave your name
and number at the beep,
I'll get right back to you.
Thanks.
This is Larry, uh,
at Pronto Printing.
Your business cards are ready.
Say, maybe when you pick 'em up,
we could go for a
drink or something.
What do you say?
Hello, Mrs. Hansfield,
this is Rosemary Barnes.
That matter we
talked about last week,
I've decided to go with
another investigator.
Sorry.
Hi, my name is Brad Loomis.
I'm with the investment firm
of James, Ashford and Town.
I'd like to talk to
you about invest...
Sorry I'm late.
Well, talk fast.
My kids have got swim
lessons in half an hour.
You heard her.
Talk fast.
Well, you... This
meeting wasn't my idea.
But your secretary
called my secretary.
Not mine.
You called.
No, he called and told my son
I was supposed meet
you two here. I did not.
What, you calling my son a liar?
Wait a minute. Hold it.
Hold it. Hold it.
What the hell's going on here?
Oh, my grandmother was right.
She always said you can tell
how well people know each other
by how intensely they argue.
Uh, Mr-Mr-Mr. Sands.
Oh, and Mr. Barr, then,
and, uh, Mrs. Proctor.
Uh, Ben Matlock.
I'm sorry for the confusion.
I called the meeting.
Would you care for a drink?
What do you want?
Uh, I'm just trying to find out
who killed Rob
Casey. You remember
Rob Casey.
Uh, he was the man
who was gonna
send each of you a set
of these.
Why would
a complete stranger
send me a photograph?
Well, he needed $40,000.
And he needed it quick.
And, uh, my guess is that, uh,
these, uh, pictures tell a story
you'd assume
the police not hear.
Are you saying
he was trying to
blackmail one of us?
Or-or all of you.
But, as I say,
that's-that's a guess.
The man with all
the answers is dead.
Uh... is there anything
else, Mr. Matlock?
Uh, as a matter of fact, yes.
Uh... party favors.
There you are.
Here you go.
Hi.
I'd like to see Jeffrey Barr.
He had some kind of
emergency meeting.
Are you interested in having
something videotaped?
Uh, no.
It's personal.
I'm an old friend of his.
Tyler Hudson.
You have heard him
speak of me, haven't you?
No.
Well, I don't get
into town very often.
I guess out of
sight, out of mind.
Do you mind if I wait?
Sure.
You can wait in my office.
Uh... out here is okay.
Excuse me.
Hello, Vid-Proof.
Oh, that's terrible.
I'm so sorry.
Hold on.
I'll pull your tape right now.
Mm-hmm.
I have your tape right
here, Mr. Franklin.
Shall I messenger it over
to your insurance company?
That's what we're here for.
If you need anything
else, just call us.
Mr. Hudson?
Hello, Linda.
How'd you get in here?
Tyler.
He's the reason your
answering machine doesn't work.
We figured you'd
stop by to see why.
Please just leave.
Somebody doesn't
want you to talk to me.
You don't understand.
Then make me understand.
They got my boy.
Someone broke in here last week
and they stole the log
I kept on Rob Casey.
And left a note.
Said they have David.
If I didn't testify
against Michael Koskoff
I'd never see him again.
I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to
buy some time.
I'm going crazy.
Did they say when
they'd contact you again?
Sometime today.
David has asthma.
If he gets upset or frightened,
he's gonna get very sick.
Does he know his medication?
He knows what he needs.
Well, he's-he's bright.
And, uh, he's inventive.
Maybe he'll figure
out a way to get it.
If whoever has him lets him.
And why would they care?
Somebody in on this thing
made a desperate move.
Very desperate.
Somebody's coming
to this drugstore
to pick up David's medicine.
He's probably in there already.
So soon?
Mr. Marshal said someone
called in the prescription.
Well, that was less
than an hour ago.
Linda, when this guy comes
out of the drugstore, be cool.
Sure. The object here
is for him to lead us
to David, okay? Okay.
All right.
Now, look, Linda,
just take it easy, okay?
This is going to work.
I promise.
Hello?
Thank you, Mr. Marshal.
There you go.
Yeah, that's him.
That's one of Dominic
Vincent's hoods.
Linda! Linda!
Where is my kid?!
Get him!
Tyler, get him!
♪ ♪
Here's the kid's prescription.
I had some
trouble picking it up.
Ben Matlock.
Hello, Ben?
Tyler, where are you?
I'm across the street
from a house at 6624
Langdon Avenue.
I saw him.
Uh, one of Dominic
Vincent's goons
just dropped off
his prescription.
Yeah, well, we can't do anything
that might get David hurt,
so just don't do anything.
Stay in your car,
watch the house.
You got it.
Right.
We have to do something.
I know.
Mr. Matlock, I'm shocked.
I respect family.
I wouldn't kidnap a kid.
Whoever took David
Hansfield works for you.
Hey, Dom?
You birdied the sucker.
All right.
I don't know anything
about this kidnapping,
but I'll look into it.
I appreciate it.
I expect to see David very soon.
With a little luck, Mr. Matlock.
You do believe
in luck, don't you?
Whatever works, Mr. Vincent.
Linda, what the hell
are you doing here?
You didn't think I was
gonna wait in the office?
I guess not.
How many men in there?
There's one, I think.
The guy that grabbed David left.
Let's go. Wait a minute.
Now, Ben specifically
said for us to wait.
Let go of me. Wait a minute!
Now, what are you gonna do,
just walk up and
knock on the door?
That's my kid in there!
You got a better idea?
Hold on a minute.
Close the door!
If you're not careful, you
might wind up getting him hurt.
Let's be smart about this, okay?
Stop or I'll shoot!
Here's pop and chips, kid.
Knock yourself out.
Oh, no!
There they go again.
And this time, I'm
going to stop him.
Hi. Do you know
anything about cars?
I think there's something
wrong with mine.
I don't know.
Please do something.
I don't know if I
can do anything.
Bless you.
Yeah, this is... See?
Your radiator's bone dry.
When's the last
time you checked it?
I don't know.
Never.
It'll be here any minute.
Hello, David.
Remember me?
You're that guy who
works for my mom.
With your mom.
I work with your mother.
Where is she? She's outside.
I want her to come in.
She wants you to come out.
No!
Hmm.
David, your mother
is waiting for you
outside.
That's what the other guy said.
No!
Hmm.
Did you have
a hose or-or a bucket? A what?!
A bucket. A bucket.
No. Maybe some,
uh, distilled water?
It-It comes in a bottle.
All right, I'll get
some of that.
That'd be great. You mean now?
Well, yeah, I mean now.
What...? What was...?
There's this thing. I
think... I think this is it.
Thing... You... What? What?
That's the kid's mother!
Oh!
Oh.
Hey, lady, get
back in the house!
Ow, lady! No!
Oh!
Hey... Move in...
Hey.
Oh. There you go.
Say, he's all right. Oh, David.
He's okay.
Let's see...
Thank you.
Vincent's hood died before
he reached the hospital.
Oh, what about the one
who was holding David?
He was one of the lesser hoods.
Oh, he just hadn't been
convicted of murder yet.
I had a feeling you'd
go after David yourself.
I couldn't help it. I... I know.
He's your son.
I'm glad I have a
hot line to the police.
Thanks.
Mm.
I've caused you
a lot of trouble.
I lied in court,
I hurt the case.
Remember I told you,
being a woman in
this business isn't easy.
Well, like the fella says,
ain't nothin' easy.
We got over one hump.
Now let's see if
we can get over...
another one.
Okay, uh, Kim,
bedtime is at 8:30.
Yuck!
9:00.
And there are
peanut butter cookies
and apple juice in the fridge
for their snack.
All right. I probably
won't be home
till late, so just feel free.
Make yourself comfortable, okay?
Okay. Don't worry about a thing.
Bye, Mom. Oh. Mmm!
Bye. Mmm!
Bye-bye, sweeties. Okay.
Bye. Listen to Kim.
All clear.
Here we go.
Phone line...
Phone line... Phone line...
Bingo. Alarm line.
Okay, alarm's off. Go.
Freeze.
Clear.
Okay.
That's it.
We're in.
Put that down
and place your hands
behind your heads!
Oh... Oh, yeah,
you're in trouble now.
Breaking into a post office
is a federal offense, gentlemen.
Oh, and ladies.
So's kidnapping.
And I want to see you
serve every minute on that.
And then there's
first-degree murder.
That's not exactly
a misdemeanor.
So who's gonna be the first
to give himself a break?
Who's gonna tell us
what's going on here?
Nobody?
Okay.
All right, take 'em downtown.
Tyler, you...?
I just might have something.
The safe and the
guns from the pictures.
Yeah.
Maybe Charles Demming
can tell us what they mean.
Here we go.
Uh, Ben Matlock, Linda
Hansfield, Charles Demming.
Pleasure.
Well, I understand you'd like me
to identify one of our safes.
If you can.
That's not one of ours.
But it has your name on it.
That's just a label.
Here, I'll show you.
You see,
somebody peeled that off
one our boxes just like that.
We would never do that.
But just to be sure,
there would be a serial
number on the bottom.
88474263.
No, that's not definitely
not one of ours.
Well, did one of these ever get
away from you, lose it, misplace it?
Uh, one was stolen once. When?
Uh, four years ago. It
was the only time anyone
ever broke in and got
away with any jewelry.
I remember that robbery.
Yeah? Yeah.
The insurance company
reimbursed me for
every item that was stolen.
Right down to the last earring.
Hey, you had a
record of everything?
I have a videotape
of everything.
Oh...
Jeffery Barr's company
did the videotaping?
Yeah, two months, two months
before the store was robbed
and nothing was
ever recovered. Hmm.
This is it, folks.
Three people
committed the break-in
while a fourth person
waited in the car outside.
Sound familiar?
Same M.O. as the post office.
Only back then,
three people did the breaking in
because Rob
Casey was still alive.
You think the guns in that safe
are the ones used
in the jewelry heist?
Tyler just called
from Ballistics,
and those guns were
not used in the heist.
You're kidding?
No.
They weren't even
manufactured till two years ago.
Neither was the safe.
And you know that label
that was on the safe?
Rob Casey put that label there?
Because he was bluffing?
And as soon as we
find out who fell for it...
Mr. Barr,
how long have you known
Mitchell Sands and Nancy Proctor?
Um, on the, on the
advice of counsel,
I invoke my Fifth
Amendment rights
and I decline to
answer that question.
Uh, how about the
decedent Rob Casey?
On the advice of counsel,
I invoke my Fifth
Amendment rights, and I...
Fine, fine, fine, fine.
Uh, Mr. Barr, uh, you
go into people's homes
and businesses and videotape
their possessions for insurance
policies, is that correct?
Yeah, that's correct.
Okay.
Uh, here is a, uh, videotape
that we subpoenaed
from your company library,
and the name of the
man you made it for
is right here on the box.
Would you read that
name aloud for us, please?
It's "Mitchell Sands."
Mitchell Sands, okay.
And your name's
on here, too. Why?
It's because you're the one
who made the videotape,
right?
Answering that question
might tend to incriminate me...
Oh, that's fine,
fine, fine. We have a
cassette player right here.
And all we have
to do is pop it in,
and we'll hear your
voice behind the camera
and see you talking to
your client Mitchell Sands
and his former
girlfriend Nancy Proctor.
All right, all right, all right,
I, uh, I had a
passing acquaintance
with both of them, but
that was four years ago.
Four years ago. Okay.
Now here's another
videotape that we subpoenaed,
and would you read the
name that's on this box?
"Charles Demming Jewelers."
Right. And the date?
"April seven, 1985."
And your name's on here, too.
That's correct.
Uh, just two months after
you made this videotape,
this jewelry store was
robbed. Do you remember that?
Vaguely.
Vaguely?!
Because of this videotape,
the insurance company
covered the entire
$2 million loss.
Now you remember?
Yes, I remember.
Yeah.
I've looked at this
tape and it's interesting.
I'm talking detail.
Anybody, anybody
who looked at this tape
would get a very good
idea of the security system
in this store, particularly
your passing acquaintance
Mitchell Sands, who was
once an electrical engineer.
Objection: relevance.
Relevancy, relevancy!
I'm gonna show relevancy!
Overruled.
Thank you.
Uh, this safe... was
found in a post office box
registered to Rob Casey.
Maybe you recognize it.
And on the bottom,
there's a sign,
little tag there that says
"Charles Demming
Jewelers." You recognize that?
No.
Well, let's see if
you recognize this.
Oh, oh-oh.
The police ran
ballistic tests on these
this morning and
dusted them for prints.
Care to guess what they found?
Look, that doesn't
mean that I killed Casey.
Say again? I said that,
that, this does not
mean I killed Rob Casey!
They found nothing.
Rob Casey was bluffing.
These were not the safe and the
guns that were used in the heist.
My guess is he got rid
of them four years ago
like he was supposed to.
But then he got to thinking.
And he went out and he
bought this safe and these guns
as kind of a little
insurance policy
in case if and when he ever
wanted to blackmail his former
associates: Mitchell Sands,
Nancy Proctor and you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Where were you at 6:00 the
night Rob Casey was killed?
I was, I was videotaping...
Don't tell me that you were
at Mr. and Mrs. Dorfmans because
I know you left
there before 5:30.
So where were
you really, Mr. Barr?
I, uh, I went to Nancy
Proctor's house.
I had to talk to her.
And did you?
No. No, she wasn't there.
So we don't know where
you were really, do we?
Yeah, ask the babysitter.
She saw me. She'll
tell you I was there.
Her name was Kim Kyoto.
She saw me! She'll say I
was there right at 6:00! Ask her!
I'm done.
If the killer isn't
Mitchell Sands,
I'll eat your hat.
I don't wear a hat.
Well, if you did, I'd eat it.
Well, according to the
biggest crime boss in the state,
he's not.
But Nancy Proctor was
at her son's piano lesson.
I checked it out myself.
I-I checked out
the ice cream parlor
she took him to afterwards.
I even know what
flavors they ordered.
Well... we're missing something.
What makes you think
we're gonna find it here?
I don't know. This is
where he was killed.
Uh...
Dadgum.
Well, I'll be dadgum.
What you got?
A 1936 proof set.
How did the fire
department miss this?
I guess they weren't
looking for something like this.
They valuable?
I look for stuff like
this all the time.
That penny: $200.
See that Buffalo Head nickel?
$700.
The dime, about $400.
The 50 cent? $2,000.
Oh.
Ooh, what's this worth?
25 cents.
Why so little?
It's a 1987 quarter.
Oh.
This would be worth
much more as a set
than if you broke it up.
You'd never break this up.
Do you think there
might be a 1936 quarter
around here somewhere?
Not if we're lucky.
Keep looking.
Chin up, wrists down.
Freeze those fingers.
Higher, higher. Sit up straight.
Elbows in.
Keep going. Steady, steady.
Feel the tempo. That's it. So,
you have more questions
about Artie Proctor?
Yes, I forgot to ask you
when I was here before.
Did his mom drop
him off for his lesson,
and then pick him up
later, or did she wait for him?
Artie's lesson is
only a half hour.
Nancy always waits for him.
So his mother was in
here from 6:00 to 6:30?
Oh, not in here, no.
No, in the library.
Parents must wait in here.
Their presence in there
would distract the students.
Hmm.
Shoulders back, wrists down.
Tempo, tempo.
Uh, do you always
keep these doors closed?
Yes.
So you wouldn't know for sure
whether she stayed or left.
No, I wouldn't.
Mrs. Proctor will be
here at 4:00 tomorrow
for Artie's regular lesson.
Shall I ask her
and then call you?
No, no, no, please
don't say anything.
All right.
Thank you for your time, though.
Uh, y-you say, uh,
Artie-Artie's regular lesson
was Wednesdays at 4:00?
Yes. But on the... BOTH: 17th...
he came at 6:00?
Oh, Mrs. Proctor
called the night before
and asked if she
could reschedule.
Artie's one of my
favorites; I said fine.
Oh, well, that's fine.
Thank you. Uh-huh.
We enjoyed that.
Casey's house is
five minutes from here.
She killed him.
She snuck out, she killed
him, she snuck back in.
Oh, he wants my spot.
The note said
if I didn't testify
against Michael Koskoff,
that I'd never see my son again.
Huh.
So is that what you did?
I testified earlier that I saw
Michael Koskoff leaving
the scene of the murder
when, in fact, I didn't
see anybody at all.
Why would someone force
you to lie in court like that?
So that Michael Koskoff
would be convicted and...
the real murderer... the
person who kidnapped my son,
would get away.
When you found your son,
he was wearing a jacket.
Yes.
I asked you to bring that
jacket to court with you today.
This is it.
I ask that this jacket be marked
Defense Exhibit
"J" for identification.
It shall be so marked.
Thank you.
Uh, is this your son's jacket?
No.
And when I examined it...
I found this label
sewn into the lining.
What does it say?
It says "Artie Proctor."
Nancy Proctor, Mr. Barr
and Mr. Sands' mutual friend,
has a son named
Artie, doesn't she?
Yes, she does.
No further questions.
No questions.
Witness may step down.
Mr. Matlock.
Call Nancy Proctor to the stand.
You recognize this coat?
Yes, it used to be my son's.
Used to be?
He lost it several weeks ago.
I have no idea how
it ended up here.
I think you have
a very good idea.
I think you're a good mother
and you would never let
anybody's little boy go
without a warm jacket.
Are you saying that I
had something to do
with the kidnapping?
You had everything
to do with it.
That is not true.
I have two small
children of my own.
I think kidnapping is
the most despicable,
the most heinous of all crimes.
And that's exactly
why you thought
you could get away with it.
You knew you had a surefire
way to get another mother...
Linda Hansfield...
To help convict Michael Koskoff
and get you off the hook
for the murder of Rob Casey.
Objection.
No foundation.
Assumes facts not in evidence.
Sustained.
Okay.
Um, uh, where were you
between 6:00 and 6:30 p.m.
on March 17?
I was at my son's
weekly piano lesson.
I was waiting for him there.
Uh, does he usually
have his lesson at 6:00?
Well, usually it's at 4:00.
I, uh, had to reschedule it.
I forget why.
But you were waiting for
him right there in the room?
Yes.
Now, are you sure?
We have spoken
with the music teacher.
Well, I was actually
in another room.
Uh-huh.
Uh, where, where did
you park that evening?
Where did I park?
Objection.
Relevance?
Your Honor, I must be able
to ask this witness
where she parked.
It goes to the alibi, and
this coat demands it.
Overruled.
So, so... thank you... Where
did you park that evening?
Which side of the
street... North or south?
The... south side.
Mm! Mm, mm, mm.
Did you get a ticket?
No.
No?
Well, uh, these
people all parked
on the same side of the
street that you say you parked,
but they all got tickets.
Do you know why?
I have no idea.
Rush hour traffic regulation.
There's a sign right
in front of the house.
Maybe because you usually
go at 4:00, you never noticed it.
Now, why did all these
people get parking tickets
and you didn't?
The meter maid
somehow missed me.
Or maybe you missed her.
Did you sneak out of that house,
drive the less than two
miles to Rob Casey's house,
go in, kill him,
drive back, sneak
back in the library
at the music teacher's just
before the lesson ended?
No.
You were in on that
jewelry store heist
four years ago, weren't you?
And everything
went fine for a while,
but then Rob Casey
began to realize
the only way out of his problems
was to blackmail you,
and you knew that he
worked for Michael Koskoff
and you knew where
the gun was kept
and you stole that gun
and you killed Rob Casey.
None of that is true.
Where'd you go after
the music lesson?
I, uh, I took my son
to get ice cream,
as I always do.
Uh-huh.
You went to a parlor
at Ninth and Maple?
Yes.
And you ordered one butter pecan
cone and one fudge ripple cone?
Yes.
And you paid $1.80 for
them in exact change?
I don't remember.
Well, the boy who waited
on you remembered...
because...
this is one of the coins
you paid him with...
A 1936 quarter.
He kept it because
he knew it was old.
He thought maybe it
was valuable, and it was
much more valuable
than he thought.
It's a proof.
Thing about a coin like this is
the only place you
can find them now is
in a collection or in a, a store
like Rob Casey worked in.
What were you doing with it?
I have no idea.
Thing about coin proofs
is you have to have
a whole set from
one year... Penny,
nickel, dime, quarter,
50-cent piece...
And Rob Casey had that.
Kept it in a plastic
box on a table.
I know because I found it.
It was melted, but
everything was there
except this quarter.
I found, I found a quarter.
It was a 1987.
Now, how do you suppose
that 1987 quarter was there,
and you wound up with this 1936?
I don't know.
How about this?
You went over there ostensibly
to give him the blackmail money.
He knew you, so he
let you in the back door.
You put your purse
down on the table
where he kept
his coin collection,
opened your purse to take
out the blackmail money,
but you took out a pistol.
I don't know what happened then.
You shot him and
he fell on the table
or he jumped at
you as you shot him
and you both fell on the table.
Anyhow, you and him and
the table and your purse
and a coin collection all
went to hell in a tea kettle.
I mean, stuff went everywhere.
Well, you had to
get out of there,
so you picked up your purse,
see if you had anything
else on the floor,
maybe lipstick or powder
puff or a comb or something.
Here's a coin, pick it up,
put it in there, get out of there.
And then you went
to the ice cream parlor
and bought some ice cream.
Only thing is you overpaid
by almost a thousand dollars.
He was blackmailing
all of you, wasn't he?
How did you get
picked to kill him?
Did, did you volunteer
or did you draw straws?
Maybe you ought
to invoke the Fifth.
How do you feel?
Happy is how I feel,
happy and, and relieved
and eager to get
back to my coin shop.
Tyler.
Congratulations.
Congratulations to you.
You know, we make
a pretty good team.
This is going to work out okay.
Uh, what is going
to work out okay?
Well, I'm glad to see you've
settled your differences.
This is going to work out okay.
What's going to work out okay?
Linda's agreed to work
with us from time to time.
Do you like hot dogs?
Uh, can't stand 'em.
This is not going
to work out okay.
www.tvsubtitles.net